<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yushi Omote</title>
    <link>http://yushiomote.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Yushi Omote</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 08:33:23 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://yushiomote.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to write x86 bare-metal hello world in Rust</title>
      <link>http://yushiomote.org/posts/baremetal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 08:33:23 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yushiomote.org/posts/baremetal/</guid>
      <description>This is the article for the 15th day of qiita advent calendar.
In this post, I&#39;m going to show you how to write a bare-metal hello-world in Rust (x86). By bare-metal hello-world, I mean the hello-world program which doesn&#39;t require any OS and starts directly on your PC from a hard disk or an USB flash drive.
Write a simple no_std program This is a typical hello-world program in Rust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing gameboy emulator in Rust</title>
      <link>http://yushiomote.org/posts/gameboy-emu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 14:04:16 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yushiomote.org/posts/gameboy-emu/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is the article for the 8th day of qiita advent calendar.
I&#39;m writing gameboy emulator in Rust.
  
I&#39;ve confirmed some major titles are playable.
 Kirby&#39;s Dream Land Super Mario Land Dr. Mario Donkey Kong Land Tetris Pokemon Red/Green The Legend of Zelda Mega Man &amp;hellip;      In this post, I&#39;m going to describe some internals of the emulator.
Instruction emulation CPU specification The CPU of the gameboy is LR35902, it&#39;s a hybrid of Zilog Z80 and Intel 8080.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chip 8 story</title>
      <link>http://yushiomote.org/posts/chip-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 11:51:05 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yushiomote.org/posts/chip-8/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is the article for the 6th day of qiita advent calendar.
Here I introduce how I played with Chip-8 these days.
What&#39;s Chip-8? Chip-8 is an interpreted programming language, which was used on some old computer systems. Mostly video games were run on them.
(from: https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/5/54/Space_intercept.png/440px-Space_intercept.png)
Emulating Chip-8 execution environment is really easy; it basically needs only 36 instructions to be emulated. The memory is a simple byte array.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compile-time linter for Redis Lua script in Rust</title>
      <link>http://yushiomote.org/posts/redis-lua/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 11:52:25 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yushiomote.org/posts/redis-lua/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is the article for the 5th day of qiita advent calendar.
It&#39;s about my WIP hobby project I&#39;ve just started.
Lua scripting in Redis Redis is a well-known high-performance key-value store. One of its interesting feature is Lua scripting.
Redis has eval command. With the command, you can let redis run a Lua script. The following example creates 5 keys by Lua script.
$ redis-cli &amp;gt; eval &amp;#39;for i=1,5 do redis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My website as Code</title>
      <link>http://yushiomote.org/posts/new-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 10:14:55 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yushiomote.org/posts/new-website/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is the article for the 2nd day of qiita advent calendar.
Hi, this is my new personal website!
My old website is still alive here (http://old.yushiomote.org), but I plan to remove it in the near future.
It&#39;s been a while since I wrote my last article. I even haven&#39;t logged in my old personal server for a long time. I forgot almost all the settings in my old personal server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Posts</title>
      <link>http://yushiomote.org/posts/old-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 06:15:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yushiomote.org/posts/old-blog/</guid>
      <description>My old posts can be found here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://yushiomote.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 04:09:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yushiomote.org/about/</guid>
      <description>Yushi Omote Rust, C/C++, Python, x86/64, Virtualization, Giroppon, Fintech
Professional history  Oct 2015 – Current  Engineer, SBI BITS (Better IT Solutions).   Apr 2014 – Sep 2015  Research Fellow, University of Tsukuba / Japan Society for the Promotion of Science.   May 2012 – Mar 2014  Contract Researcher, National Institute for Agro-Environmental Sciences.    Publications  OS-Independent Live Migration Scheme for Bare-metal Clouds.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>